MIKE RIVERA

San Diego, CA 92126

Phone: 858.603.6731 | Email: info@michaelsrivera.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/msrivera/ | Github: https://github.com/sweetmike |

Portfolio: https://michaelsrivera.com/

SUMMARY

Highly organized individual with over 10 years of problem solving experience as a Bicycle Service Technician in search of a new career path in the tech industry as a Full Stack Web Developer. I hope to obtain a position in which I can combine both the skills in front-end and back-end web development with my desire to improve and strong work ethic to assist a company in meeting and surpassing its goals for success!

SKILLS

Languages: HTML5 | CSS | JavaScript | SQL | JSX

Tools & Frameworks: React.js | Bootstrap | Materialize | Handlebars.js | Axios | JQuery | Node.js | MySQL |

MongoDB | Mongoose | Express.js | ES6

Concepts: Responsive Design | MVC Pattern | C.R.U.D. | APIs | MERN Stack | Big O Notation | Web

Scraping

PROJECTS

MADPass

Github - https://github.com/DarrenVictoriano/MAD-Protection Deployed - https://fathomless-garden-46795.herokuapp.com/

- MADPass is the basic implementation of a password manager allowing a user to only remember one login and password for the app itself. All other login credentials are encrypted and stored in the user's Vault to be accessed quickly and easily.
- Core responsibilities included utilizing React to create multiple modals for capturing user input, using Axios for making client side HTTP requests, and general bug fixing.
- MongoDB | Express.js | React.js | Node.js | bcrypt | crypto.js | JWT

Reflect

Github - https://github.com/IrvinGutierrez6117/Project 2
Deployed - https://mindblog.herokuapp.com/

- A journaling application that allows a user to record their daily thoughts while recording their mood and time of day to be used in generating graphs showing the data supplied.
- Core responsibilities included working with Sequelize and MySQL to construct the database, create code for searching and retrieving data, and general bug fixing.
- HTML | CSS | JQuery | Node.js | Express.js | MySQL | Sequelize

EXPERIENCE

Service Department Manager Trek Bicvcle Superstore

2014 – Present

San Diego, CA

Monitored and ensured all repairs were completed correctly and efficiently through detailed communication, planning, and skills training between myself and my staff.

Kev Accomplishments:

- Obtained multiple technical certifications from multiple industry manufacturers including Shimano, SRAM, Trek, etc.
- Received continuous positive reviews and praise from numerous satisfied customers both through the company review application as well as in person.

District Bicycle Tech Trainer / Dept. Manager

2000 - 2014

Sport Chalet

San Diego & Porter Ranch, CA

Coordinated and conducted technical training clinics for Bicycle Dept. employees within my district for General Assembly and Master Mechanic certifications.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of California San Diego | San Diego, CA | 2019 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.is & ReactJS.